Guide to the Anaconda Copper Mining Company records 1876-1974
Montana Historical Society
- General Office
  - Subject Files [General Office, Butte]
    - #148 Hardware Department cash requirements, 1920-1921 (Box-folder 122 / 11)
    - #161 Utah corporate filings: Alice Department and Diamond Coal and Coke Company, 1919-1928 (Box-folder 122 / 12)
    - #166 Interstate Lumber Company profit and loss accounts, 1919-1928 (Box-folder 122 / 13)
    - #173 Interstate Lumber Company appropriations, etc., 1919-1928 (Box-folder 122 / 14)
    - #178 Washoe Sampler; Golden Curry Consolidated Mining Company, 1919-1924 (Box-folder 122 / 15)
    - #181 Great Falls Reduction Department and Butte Mines appropriations, 1917, 1920-1927 (Box-folder 122 / 16-17)
    - #183 Great Falls Reduction Department, 1917, 1920-1928 (Box-folder 122 / 18)
    - #185-186 Great Falls Reduction Department: K.B. Frazer, 1916-1926 (Box-folder 122 / 19-21)
    - #187-188 Great Falls Reduction Department payroll, 1916-1928 (Box-folder 123 / 1-2)
    - #189 Cupreous materials and zinc, 1916-1917, 1928 (Box-folder 123 / 3)
    - #190 Portage Land Company, 1917, 1921-1924 (Box-folder 123 / 4)
    - #191 Zinc; payroll, 1920-1923, 1927-1928 (Box-folder 123 / 5)
    - #192 Great Falls Reduction Department cash disbursements, 1920-1921 (Box-folder 123 / 6)
    - #201 Metallurgical inventories, 1916-1920 (Box-folder 123 / 7)
    - #202 Washoe Reduction Works fuel stocks on hand, 1916-1919 (Box-folder 123 / 8)
    - #203 Washoe Reduction Works collections (includes rents on company houses), 1915-1925 (Box-folder 123 / 9-13)
    - #203 Washoe Reduction Works collections (includes rents on company houses), 1926-1928 (Box-folder 124 / 1-3)
    - #204 Washoe Reduction Works, 1914-1928 (Box-folder 124 / 4)
    - #205 Washoe Reduction Works cash requirements, 1914-1919 (Box-folder 124 / 5)
    - #205 Washoe Reduction Works wage and salary scales, garnishments, 1915-1928 (Box-folder 124 / 6)
    - #208 Washoe Reduction Works appropriations, 1914-1917 (Box-folder 124 / 7-8)
    - #208 Washoe Reduction Works appropriations, 1918-1928 (Box-folder 125 / 1-2)
    - #209 Deer Lodge Valley Farms, 1912-1923 (Box-folder 125 / 3)
    - #210 Washoe Reduction Works metallurgical and cost sheets (re compiling of), 1916-1928 (Box-folder 125 / 4)
    - #213 Framing Plant, 1924-1926 (Box-folder 125 / 5)
    - #214 Arsenic sales, 1922-1928 (Box-folder 125 / 6)
    - #215 Copper Extraction Company, 1912-1915 (Box-folder 125 / 7)
    - #216 Washoe Reduction Works power line, 1917 (Box-folder 125 / 8)
    - #217 Washoe Reduction Works (includes property transfers, expenses, royalty payments, etc.), 1914-1928 (Box-folder 125 / 9-11)
    - #218 Miscellaneous (includes Liberty Bonds, property holdings, telephone system, etc.), 1918-1926 (Box-folder 125 / 12)
    - #219 Fertilizer, 1926-1928 (Box-folder 125 / 13)
    - #220 East Helena Slag Treatment Plant, 1927-1928 (Box-folder 125 / 14)
    - #221 Foundry Department inventory, 1920-1925 (Box-folder 125 / 15)
    - #223 Foundry Department payroll, 1920-1928 (Box-folder 125 / 16)
    - #225 Foundry Department depreciation, 1923 (Box-folder 126 / 1)
    - #226 Foundry Department appropriations, 1920-1929 (Box-folder 126 / 2)
    - #228 Foundry Department office equipment, 1922-1926 (Box-folder 126 / 3)
    - #228 Foundry Department deposits and disbursements, 1920-1921 (Box-folder 126 / 4)
    - #231 Anaconda Brick Department payroll, 1920-1925 (Box-folder 126 / 5)
    - #234 Anaconda Brick Department costs, 1920-1926 (Box-folder 126 / 6)
    - #235 Anaconda Brick Department appropriations, 1920-1927 (Box-folder 126 / 7)
    - #236 Great Falls Brick Department business statements, 1920-1928 (Box-folder 126 / 8)
    - #240 Great Falls Brick Department depreciation, 1920 (Box-folder 126 / 9)
    - #241 Hotel Department payroll, 1927-1928 (Box-folder 126 / 10)
    - #248 Hotel Department, 1928 (Box-folder 126 / 11)
    - #251 Electric Light and Railway Department, 1926-1928 (Box-folder 126 / 12)
    - #253 Electric Light and Railway Department salaries, 1926-1928 (Box-folder 126 / 13)
    - #259 Electric Light and Railway Department annual report to Public Service Commission, 1924, 1928 (Box-folder 126 / 14)
    - #281 Lumber Department property, 1924-1928 (Box-folder 126 / 15)
    - #281 Bonner Lumber Department business statements, 1911-1914 (Box-folder 126 / 16)
    - #282 Bonner Lumber Department personnel, 1912-1914, 1924-1928 (Box-folder 126 / 17)
    - #283 Bonner Lumber Department, 1912-1914, 1924-1928 (Box-folder 126 / 18)
    - #286 Bonner Lumber Department appropriations, 1912-1914, 1924-1928 (Box-folder 126 / 19)
    - #288 Bonner Lumber Department; Missoula Opera House, 1924-1928 (Box-folder 126 / 20)
    - #304 St. Regis Lumber Department sale of equipment, 1928 (Box-folder 126 / 21)
    - #316 Hope Lumber Manufacturing Company bonds, 1920-1927 (Box-folder 126 / 22)
    - #317 Hope Lumber Manufacturing Company business statements, 1920-1927 (Box-folder 126 / 23)
    - #320 Hope Lumber Manufacturing Company payroll, 1920-1924 (Box-folder 126 / 24)
    - #321, 324 Belt properties, 1919-1923 (Box-folder 126 / 25)
    - #327 G.W. Merkle Coal Company, Belt, production and royalties, 1919-1924 (Box-folder 126 / 26)
    - #332 Belt Mercantile Company salaries, 1918 (Box-folder 126 / 27)
    - #336 G.W. Merkle Coal Company's Mercantile Department, Belt, 1918 (Box-folder 126 / 28)
    - #338 Sale of Belt Mercantile Department to G.W. Merkle Coal Company, 1918 (Box-folder 126 / 29)
    - #386 Lumber Department audit expense, 1926 (Box-folder 126 / 30)
    - #387 Audits, 1926 (Box-folder 126 / 31)
    - #390 Traffic Department, 1927-1928 (Box-folder 126 / 32)
    - #401 Deer Lodge Valley Farms Company deeds and releases (some for smoke damage), 1919-1928 (Box-folder 126 / 33)
    - #402 Deer Lodge Valley Farms Company; Mill Creek Irrigation Company stock, 1926 (Box-folder 126 / 34)
    - #403 Deer Lodge Valley Farms Company accounts receivable, 1919-1925 (Box-folder 127 / 1)
    - #404 Deer Lodge Valley Farms Company checks, etc., 1919-1923 (Box-folder 127 / 2)
    - #404 Deer Lodge Valley Farms Company, 1919-1921 (Box-folder 127 / 3)
    - #405 Deer Lodge Valley Farms Company horses, 1919-1928 (Box-folder 127 / 4)
    - #411 Blackfoot Land Development Company land sales, 1919-1927 (Box-folder 127 / 5)
    - #413 Blackfoot Land Development Company profit and loss, 1919-1925 (Box-folder 127 / 6)
    - #416 Blackfoot Land Development Company, 1919-1923 (Box-folder 127 / 7)
    - #417 Blackfoot Land Development Company, Swamp Creek Project, 1924 (Box-folder 127 / 8)
    - #418 Blackfoot Land Development Company expenses and deposits, 1920-1921 (Box-folder 127 / 9)
    - #420 Thompson Falls Mercantile Company, 1924-1928 (Box-folder 127 / 10)
    - #421 Sand Coulee Coal Department payroll, banking; agreement with Lochray Coal Company; Miners Bank of Sand Coulee receivership, 1913-1927 (Box-folder 127 / 11)
    - #423 Sand Coulee Coal Department business statements (includes inventory for Lochray Coal Company), 1914-1929 (Box-folder 127 / 12)
    - #424 Sand Coulee Coal Department, 1914-1925 (Box-folder 127 / 13)
    - #425 Sand Coulee Coal Department forms, office supplies, 1914-1925 (Box-folder 127 / 14)
    - #426 Sand Coulee Coal Department bad debts, 1920-1925 (Box-folder 127 / 15)
    - #427 Sand Coulee Coal Department land exchanges, 1914-1927 (Box-folder 127 / 16)
    - #428 Sand Coulee Coal Department depreciation, 1916-1923 (Box-folder 127 / 17)
    - #429 Sand Coulee Coal Department appropriations, 1914-1920 (Box-folder 127 / 18)
    - #430 Sand Coulee Coal Department business statements, 1914-1922 (Box-folder 127 / 19)
    - #431 Sand Coulee Coal Department, 1918-1924 (Box-folder 127 / 20)
    - #461 Boiler insurance and inspection of Butte mines, 1915-1917 (Box-folder 127 / 21-23)
    - #461 Boiler insurance and inspection of Butte mines, 1919-1925 (Box-folder 128 / 1-2)
    - #461 Boiler insurance, 1926-1928 (Box-folder 128 / 3-4)
    - #462 Fire insurance, 1915-1928 (Box-folder 128 / 5)
    - #463 Purchasing Department insurance, 1919-1928 (Box-folder 128 / 6)
    - #464 Plate glass insurance; also includes Hardware Department, 1915-1917, 1925-1928 (Box-folder 128 / 7)
    - #466 Insurance on Great Falls Reduction Works, 1915-1928 (Box-folder 128 / 8)
    - #468 Insurance on Brick Plant, 1916-1924 (Box-folder 129 / 1)
    - #469 Insurance on Washoe Reduction Works, 1915-1928 (Box-folder 129 / 2-5)
    - #470 Insurance on Anaconda Ball Park and miscellaneous Anaconda properties, 1925-1927 (Box-folder 129 / 6)
    - #471 Insurance on Copper City Commercial Company; H.C. Gardiner; Darby; et al., 1917-1928 (Box-folder 129 / 7)
    - #472 Insurance on Deer Lodge Valley Farms Company and H.C. Gardiner, 1915-1928 (Box-folder 129 / 8)
    - #473 Insurance on Foundry, 1917-1922 (Box-folder 129 / 9)
    - #475 Insurance on Anaconda Electric Light and Railway, Waterworks, Townsite, 1915-1927 (Box-folder 129 / 10)
    - #476 Insurance on Hamilton Departments, 1915-1925 (Box-folder 129 / 11)
    - #477 Insurance on Bonner Lumber Department, 1915-1928 (Box-folder 129 / 12)
    - #478 Insurance on St. Regis Lumber Department, 1916-1928 (Box-folder 129 / 13)
    - #479 Insurance on Interstate Lumber Department, Missoula, 1915-1928 (Box-folder 129 / 14)
    - #480 Insurance on Washoe Coal Department, 1915-1925 (Box-folder 130 / 1)
    - #481 Insurance on G.W. Merkle Coal Company, 1925-1928 (Box-folder 130 / 2)
    - #483 Insurance on Diamond Coal and Coke Company, 1920-1928 (Box-folder 130 / 3)
    - #484 Insurance on Mountain Trading Company, 1920-1922 (Box-folder 130 / 4)
    - #485 Insurance on Hope, St. Regis, and Hamilton Lumber Departments, 1920-1926 (Box-folder 130 / 5)
    - #486 Insurance, 1921-1926 (Box-folder 130 / 6)
    - #487 Insurance on Butte buildings, 1920-1927 (Box-folder 130 / 7)
    - #489 Insurance on automobiles, 1920-1927 (Box-folder 130 / 8)
    - #490 Insurance on Sand Coulee Coal Department, 1920-1927 (Box-folder 130 / 9)
    - #491 Insurance on Chicago Rolling Mills Department, 1920-1927 (Box-folder 130 / 10)
    - #492 Insurance on Conda, Idaho, Fertilizer Department, 1921-1928 (Box-folder 130 / 11)
    - W.A. Clark property transfer: correspondence, 1928-1935 (Box-folder 130 / 12)
    - W.A. Clark property transfer: securities taken over, 1928 (Box-folder 130 / 13)
    - W.A. Clark property transfer: working papers, 1928 (Box-folder 130 / 14)
    - W.A. Clark property transfer: Butte Electric Railway Company, 1928 (Box-folder 130 / 15-16)
    - W.A. Clark property transfer: Butte Miner Company, 1928 (Box-folder 131 / 1)
    - W.A. Clark property transfer: Clark-Montana Realty Company agreement, 1928 August (Box-folder 131 / 2)
    - W.A. Clark property transfer: Clark-Montana Realty Company working papers, 1928 (Box-folder 131 / 3)
    - W.A. Clark property transfer: Elm Orlu Mining Company, 1928 (Box-folder 131 / 4)
    - W.A. Clark property transfer: Montana Hardware Company, 1928 (Box-folder 131 / 5)
    - W.A. Clark property transfer: Moulton Mining Company, 1928 (Box-folder 131 / 6)
    - W.A. Clark property transfer: Timber Butte Milling Company, 1928 (Box-folder 131 / 7)
    - W.A. Clark property transfer: Western Lumber Company, 1928 (Box-folder 131 / 8-10)
    - W.A. Clark property transfer: summary of purchases, 1928 (Volume 242)
    - Dispute with Montana Union Railway and Union Pacific Railway, 1889-1892 (Box-folder 131 / 11-12)
    - Employees missing and killed in action, World War II: A-H, 1942-1946 (Box-folder 131 / 13)
    - Employees missing and killed in action, World War II: I-Z, 1942-1946 (Box-folder 132 / 1)
    - Employees missing and killed in action, World War II: miscellaneous, 1942-1946 (Box-folder 132 / 2)
    - Northern Pacific timber lands, 1898-1899 (Box-folder 132 / 3)
  - Miscellany
    - Boiler inspectors' certificates, 1890-1891 (Box-folder 132 / 4)
    - Descriptions of corporate records in various vaults, circa 1960s (Box-folder 132 / 5)
    - Employees' citizenship register, undated (Box-folder 132 / 6)
    - Historical talks and articles, 1903-1965 (Box-folder 132 / 7)
    - "History of Butte," by Judge W.D. Murray, 1962 September (Box-folder 132 / 8)
    - List of coal land declaratory statements, Belt, 1897 (Box-folder 132 / 9)
    - List of deeds, water rights, financial records, etc. sent by departments to General Office, 1896-1916 (Box-folder 132 / 10)
    - "Mining history of Butte," by Ed Bonner, 1962 (Box-folder 132 / 11)
    - "Miscellaneous Papers" (re Bitterroot Extension, Silver Lake land, and Bonner spur), 1899-1900 (Box-folder 132 / 12)
    - Painting standards and paint specifications, 1937, 1952 (Box-folder 132 / 13)
    - "Patent record for converter methods for Bessemerizing copper matte", 1910 (Box-folder 132 / 14)
    - "Specifications for extension to Pulverized Coal Plant for Raritan Copper Works", 1927 (Box-folder 132 / 15)
    - "Specifications for two-story brick building, Anaconda, Montana", circa 1897 (Box-folder 132 / 16)
    - Subscription list for relief of California earthquake sufferers, 1906 (Box-folder 132 / 17)
    - Turner Hall Association stock certificate, 1897 (Box-folder 132 / 18)
  - Clippings
    - Judge George M. Bourquin's decision in Poser vein case, 1927 (Box-folder 132 / 19)
    - Miscellaneous (includes Greater Butte Project, future of Butte, Cornwall's influence on American mining, and talks by company officials), 1950-1970 (Box-folder 132 / 20)
  - Miscellany (Continued)
    - #32 "Original Mine 1" Butte Mining District Survey Book, circa 1910-1919 (Box-folder 132A / 1)
    - #79 "Mt. Con. Wild Bill - #6" Butte Mining District Survey Book, circa 1910-1919 (Box-folder 132A / 2)
    - #109 "Cross Section Book 376" Butte Mining District Survey Book, circa 1910-1919 (Box-folder 132A / 3)
- Alice Gold And Silver Mining Company / Alice Department
  - Outgoing Correspondence
    - Letterpress book (includes deed transfers), 1880 May-December (Box-folder 133 / 1)
  - Financial Records
    - Cash book, 1910-1916 (Box-folder 133 / 2)
    - Cost sheets (six-month reports), 1916-1919, 1928-1931 (Volume 243)
    - General ledger, 1908-1927 (Volume 244)
    - Journal, 1908-1916 (Box-folder 133 / 3)
    - Journal, 1916-1930 (Volume 245- 246)
    - Transcript of books, 1909-1911 (Volume 247)
- Anaconda Coal Company
  - Financial Records
    - Cash book, 1900 May-June (Box-folder 133 / 4)
    - Cash book, 1900 July- 1902 May (Volume 248)
    - General ledger, 1900-1902 (Volume 249)
    - General ledger index, 1900-1902 (Box-folder 133 / 5)
    - Inventories, 1900, 1903 (Box-folder 133 / 6)
    - Journal, 1900 May-June (Box-folder 133 / 7)
    - Journal, 1900 July- 1902 June (Volume 250)
    - Petty ledger, 1900 May-November (Box-folder 134 / 1-2)
    - Petty ledger, 1900 July-December (Volume 251- 252)
    - Petty ledger index, 1900 July-December (Box-folder 134 / 3)
    - Profit and loss statement, 1900 (Box-folder 134 / 4)
    - Sales book, 1900 (Volume 253- 255)
- Anaconda Fluming Company
  - Financial Records
    - Cash book, 1887-1898 (Volume 256)
    - Daybook, 1889-1896 (Volume 256a)
    - Journal, 1887-1901 (Volume 257)
    - Ledger, 1887-1898 (Volume 258)
    - Petty ledger index, 1887-1898 (Volume 259)
    - Miscellaneous (includes accounts, disbursements), 1889-1894 (Box-folder 134 / 5)
- Anaconda Meat Company
  - Financial Records
    - Cash book, 1890-1894 (Box-folder 135 / 1-2)
    - Ledger, 1890-1892 (Box-folder 135 / 3)
  - Organizational Records
    - Record book (includes bylaws, minutes), 1893-1897 (Box-folder 135 / 4)
- Anaconda Townsite Company / Townsite Department
  - Incoming Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous (re shipment of trees), 1895-1896 (Box-folder 136 / 1)
  - Outgoing Correspondence
    - Letterpress book, 1895-1897 (Box-folder 136 / 2)
  - Financial Records
    - Business statements, 1901-1956 (Volume 260- 261)
    - Cash book, 1897-1908 (Volume 262)
    - Insurance policies on Anaconda Athletic Park grandstand, 1898-1908 (Box-folder 136 / 3)
    - Inventory of lots, 1895, 1897, 1930, 1931 (Box-folder 136 / 4)
    - Ledger, 1895-1896 (Box-folder 136 / 5)
    - Ledger, 1895-1905 (Volume 263)
    - Lot book, 1883-1895 (Box-folder 136 / 6)
    - Lot book, 1893-1957 (Volume 264)
    - Rents, 1897-1912 (Volume 265)
    - Transcript of books, 1897 (Box-folder 136 / 7)
    - Transcript of books, 1911-1922 (Box-folder 137 / 1-4)
    - Trial balance book, 1895-1897 (Volume 266)
    - U.S. corporate income tax, 1918-1919 (Box-folder 137 / 5)
    - Voucher register, 1897-1911 (Volume 267)
    - Miscellaneous (includes profit and loss, journal entries), 1896-1904 (Box-folder 137 / 6)
  - Legal Documents
    - Deeds, leases, etc., 1893-1913 (Box-folder 137 / 7)
- Anaconda Water Company / Waterworks Department
  - Outgoing Correspondence
    - Letterpress book (includes history of beginning of company), 1890-1898 (Volume 268)
  - Financial Records
    - Balance sheets, profit and loss, 1895-1904 (Box-folder 137 / 8)
    - Business statements, 1892-1897 (Box-folder 137 / 9)
    - Business statements, 1901-1937 (Volume 269- 270)
    - Cash book, 1888-1892 (Box-folder 138 / 1-2)
    - Cost of new construction, 1898 (Box-folder 138 / 3)
    - Daybook, 1888-1892 (Box-folder 138 / 4)
    - Inventory, 1930-1931, undated (Box-folder 138 / 5)
    - Ledger, 1888-1889 (Box-folder 138 / 6)
    - Ledger, 1895-1898 (Volume 271)
    - Transcript of books, 1911 (Box-folder 138 / 7)
    - Transcript of books, 1912-1922 (Box-folder 139 / 1-11)
    - U.S. corporate income tax, 1918-1919 (Box-folder 139 / 12)
    - Voucher register, 1898-1906 (Volume 272)
  - Legal Documents
    - Notices of water rights, 1898 (Box-folder 139 / 13)
  - Organizational Records
    - Letter re charter granted by City of Anaconda, 1913 (Box-folder 139 / 14)
    - Stock certificate book, 1891 (Box-folder 139 / 15)
  - Miscellany
    - Injury reports, 1898-1930 (Box-folder 139 / 16)
    - "Rules for operation of valves on pipeline of reservoir system", undated (Box-folder 139 / 17)
    - "Specifications for excavating and refilling of water main", 1895 (Box-folder 139 / 18)
    - Water rate change study (Includes listing of residences, number of rooms, toilets, etc.), 1935 (Volume 273)
- Anselmo Mining Corporation
  - General Correspondence
    - Anaconda Copper Mining Company, 1925-1926 (Box-folder 140 / 1)
    - Anselmo Mining Corporation, New York office, 1925-1926 (Box-folder 140 / 2)
    - U.S. government, 1925-1926 (Box-folder 140 / 3)
    - Wolcott and Company, 1926 (Box-folder 140 / 4)
  - Financial Records
    - Cash book, 1918-1926 (Box-folder 140 / 5)
    - Copper ore settlements with Anaconda Copper Mining Company, 1925-1926 (Box-folder 140 / 6)
    - Cost sheets, 1923-1929 (Volume 274)
    - Journal, 1917-1927 (Box-folder 140 / 7)
    - Ledger, 1918-1925 (Volume 275)
    - Montana assessment of net proceeds of mines tax, 1923-1925 (Box-folder 140 / 8)
    - Montana corporate license tax, 1922-1925 (Box-folder 140 / 9)
    - Report to Federal Trade Commission (re copper ore lands), 1925 (Box-folder 140 / 10)
    - Trial balance, 1926 (Box-folder 140 / 11)
    - U.S. capital stock tax, 1924-1926 (Box-folder 140 / 12)
    - U.S. corporate income tax, 1922-1925 (Box-folder 140 / 13)
    - Voucher register, 1918-1926 (Volume 276)
    - Wage reports to accident insurance providers, 1924-1926 (Box-folder 140 / 14)
  - Legal Documents
    - Hospital contract, 1925 (Box-folder 140 / 15)
  - Organizational Records
    - Annual statement of corporation, 1924-1926 (Box-folder 140 / 16)
- Arlington Mining Company
  - Interoffice Correspondence
    - Letterpress book: Henry Williams to George F. Crane, 1881-1886 (Box-folder 140 / 17)
  - Financial Records
    - Accounts and ore statements, 1885-1898 (Box-folder 141 / 1)
    - Cash book, 1890-1902 (Box-folder 141 / 2)
    - Expense journal, 1880-1883 (Box-folder 141 / 3)
    - Journal, 1890-1895 (Box-folder 141 / 4-5)
    - Ledger, 1890-1898 (Box-folder 142 / 1)
    - Ore receipts: Star West lease, 1890-1891 (Box-folder 142 / 2)
  - Legal Documents
    - Abstract of title: Mountain Boy lode, undated (Box-folder 142 / 3)
    - Abstract of title: Star West lode, undated (Box-folder 142 / 4)
- Arsenic Department
  - Financial Records
    - Business statements, 1920-1950 (Volume 277- 279)
- Atlantic Mines Company
  - Financial Records
    - Cash book, 1915-1916 (Volume 280)
    - Financial reports, 1913-1916 (Volume 281- 281a)
    - General ledger, 1915-1916 (Volume 282)
    - General ledger trial balance sheets, 1915-1916 (Volume 283)
    - Journal, 1915-1916 (Volume 284)
    - Payroll, 1915 (Volume 285)
    - Voucher register, 1913-1914 (Box-folder 142 / 5)
- Basic Magnesium, Inc.
  - Financial Records
    - Record of existing conditions, personnel, and operations, 1942 October (Box-folder 142 / 6)
    - Record of contractual obligations, 1942 October (Box-folder 143 / 1)
- Bears Den Royalties, Inc. (K.B. Frazer)
  - Financial Records
    - Frazer-MacDonald Partnership (includes balance sheets, financial statements, and corporate histories for Bears Den, Sunburst, Liberty Dome, and other oil properties), 1926-1930 (Volume 286)
    - Transcript of books, 1927-1932 (Volume 287)
  - Minutes
    - Minutes, 1933 (Box-folder 143 / 2)
  - Clipping
    - Scrapbook (re Bears Den oil field), 1929-1930 (Volume 288)
- Belt Mercantile Company / Mercantile Department (Belt)
  - Outgoing Correspondence
    - Letterpress book, 1901-1910 (Box-folder 143 / 3)
  - Financial Records
    - Business statements, 1900-1919 (Volume 289)
    - Ledger, 1895-1905 (Volume 290- 291)
    - Ledger index, 1898-1905 (Box-folder 143 / 4)
    - Payroll, 1916-1918 (Box-folder 143 / 5)
    - Transcript of books, 1895-1916 (Box-folder 144 / 1-8)
    - Transcript of books (department transferred to G.W. Merkle Coal Company, June 1918), 1917-1918 (Box-folder 145 / 1-2)
    - Transcript of trial balance sheets (G.W. Merkle Coal Company investment), 1919 (Box-folder 145 / 3)
    - U.S. corporate income tax, 1919 (Box-folder 145 / 4)
- Big Blackfoot Milling Company / Lumber Department
  - General Correspondence
    - Manhattan Fuel and Lumber Company, 1900 (Box-folder 145 / 5)
    - Montana Pulp and Paper Company, 1900 (Box-folder 145 / 6)
  - Financial and Production Records
    - Balance sheet and profit and loss, 1901 (Box-folder 145 / 7)
    - "Mining timbers and planks shipped to Anaconda Copper Mining Company, Butte and Boston Consolidated Mining Company, Parrot Silver and Copper Company, and Washoe Copper Company", 1900-1902 (Box-folder 145 / 8-9)
    - Miscellaneous (includes statement of standing timber purchased, profit and loss), 1899-1903 (Box-folder 145 / 10)
    - Anaconda Agency balance sheets, 1896-1901 (Box-folder 145 / 11)
    - Anaconda Agency business statements, 1901-1911 (Volume 292)
    - Anaconda Agency cash books, 1898-1902 (Volume 293)
    - Anaconda Agency general ledger, 1898-1902 (Volume 294)
    - Anaconda Agency general ledger index, 1898-1902 (Box-folder 146 / 1)
    - Anaconda Agency general ledger index [Archives Map Case], 1898-1902 (Oversize-folder 1)
    - Anaconda Agency journal, 1898-1902 (Volume 295)
    - Anaconda Agency ledger, 1897-1902 (Volume 296- 297)
    - Anaconda Agency petty ledger, 1899-1900 (Volume 298)
    - Anaconda Agency petty ledger index, 1899-1900 (Box-folder 146 / 2)
    - Anaconda Agency petty ledger index [Archives Map Case], 1899-1900 (Oversize-folder 1)
    - Anaconda Agency purchase abstract, 1898 November-1899 December (Volume 299)
    - Anaconda Agency sales book, 1898 December-1899 February (Volume 300)
    - Anaconda, Butte, and Columbia Falls agencies transcripts, 1897-1898 (Volume 301)
    - Bonita Agency customers' ledger, 1896-1898 (Volume 302)
    - Bonita Agency journal, 1898-1899 (Volume 303)